Guide to the Pittsburgh & Lake Erie Railroad Company Records, 1860-1999 AIS.1982.23
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pittsburgh & Lake Erie Railroad, 1860-1999; VII.
  - Engineering, 1850-1944; 1.
    - Proposals for New Telephone Switch P&LE, Pittsburgh Telephone Co. Bell Telephone Co. F/S Communications Corp. North Pittsburgh Telephone Co., Gray Communications, 1981-1982 (Box 78)
    - Files 3177- 3283 (Elimination of grade crossing Neville Island, M.C.B. Building at McKees Rocks, etc), 1920s (Box 79)
    - New Storehouse and Oil House near Roundhouse, Haselton, Brotherhood of railway and steamship clerks, 1920-1950 (Box 80)
    - Seamon Co. Diesel Servicing Facility KS, Pgh. Des-Moines Steel Fab. Steel for Locomotive Repair Shop KS, Track layout Diesel Shop KS, Diesel Shop Cranes, Overhead Bridges Diesel Shop KS, Diesel Shop KS, Coach Shop KS, Right of way for Aliquippa and Parke Station, 1983 (Box 81)
    - Elizabeth Highway Bridge (1939), dismantling old and new and abandoned tracks and buildings (1953), requisition for ties from purchasing agent and number needed for 1955, requisition for ties from purchasing agent and number needed for 1951, requisition for ties from purchasing agent for 1956, budgets from 1952-54, reports of weekly maintenance situation rail, ties, ballast, and tamping (1953-54), capital expenditures quarterly statements, ICC reports "Circulars 31-7 and Circular" (1955), 1939-1955 (Box 82)
    - 13-G Youngstown Sheet & Tube Bridge, 13-F Youngstown Sheet & Tube Bridge, 16-A Hazelton Interlocking Plant, 18-A Hazelton to Lake Shore Branch (1901), 18-B Hazelton to Lake Shore Branch (1901), 18-D Hazelton to Lake Shore Branch (1901), 18-E Hazelton to Lake Shore Branch including Center St. Crossing with B&O and 205 (Box 83)
    - Additions and necessities (gate crossings, buildings, etc) (Box 89)
    - Right of way, tracks, crossings, grades, some blueprints, leases, derailment, 1897-1965 (Box 93-98)
    - Sidetrack, American Chemsol Co. Standard Oil- 1947, study of term. of agreements with Erie RR Youngstown Territory, New Erie Station and office building, Youngstown (1921), P&LE-NYC percentages passenger Sta. and Switching (1925), Freight Warehouse, Belmont Ave. Youngstown (1925), Erie Railroad signals (1931), Siding Crucible Steel Co. KS (1902), Kendall Coal and Coke, Tyrone Branch, Broadford (1930), Building at Haselton (1905), R of W at Lynch (1905), R of W at Beaver Falls(1902), retaining wall, Republic Iron PGH (1905), R of W Robinson (1909), Xing watchman (1944), Siding New Castle Asphalt Block Co (1901), Commercial Sash and Door Co, Beaver Falls (1905), R of W Ohio Connecting Bridge West End Pgh (1913), Hartman Dam, R of W, retaining walls and bridges (1890), 1900-1955 (Box 99-100)
    - Engineering Files: (43) KS Power House- 1902, (55) Sand House, Marchand -1915, (57) FCC Radio Licence, (60) Station at Marchland- 1903, (61) Newell Yard -1947, (63) Drinking Water, Yard Office, Newell -1943, (63) Newell Water Plant - 1929, (67) Monessen Yard -1902, (69) Sidetrack A and P Monessen- 1947, (70A) Monessen Freight Sta. -1947, (72) -1903, (79A) Glassport Yard- 1897, (85) Boiler Washing -1903, (96) Gardner Ave. Yd. New Castle (1900), 1900-1960s (Box 101)
    - Engineering Files: 3rd St. Coraopolis (1904), R of W, Lucas, Lockhart Iron and Steel, KS, R of W Braddock (1904), 34th St. Yard Pgh, Hays, Keystone Iron and Metal, Terminal Coal Co., New Glenwood Bridge, Hays, American Oil Co., Lucas (1935), Reiber St. Footbridge, New Castle (1896), Sidetrack, Ellwood Stone Co. (1899), 1909-1959 (Box 102)
    - Track switches, etc. (blueprints), 1900-1980 (Box 105)
    - Station and rail shops (1938), Pennsylvania RR Freight Terminal and Facilities, Diagram of P&LE RR (1945), Montour RR connection with P&LE (1937), Plan of Station Grounds (1909), Neville Interlocking Plant (1918), P&LE Truck Repair Shop (1927), P&LE Pittsburgh to Youngstown Location of Vacant Land Available for Lease (1930), Reconditioning Room Freight House Pittsburgh (1927), Pittsburgh Terminal Train Shed Design for Platform (1898), Plans Showing Location and details of Drinking Water Lines and Fountains in Freight House and Central Warehouse (1917), Location of Monongahela Connecting RR (1895), Pittsburgh Terminal Station Proposed Concrete Platform (1935), Organization of Department Slides, Early 1900s (Box 130)
    - P&LE and Eastern Railroad Companies agreement, Engineering Files - Damage to Roadway During Flood (1937), Blueprints and Estimate of Cost and Correspondence (Airport Parkway), Engine logs Montour Railroad, 1930s-1940s (Box 134)
    - Floor Plans Of Modernization Layout for Central Warehouse, Table of Contents: 1) Plot plan, 2) elevation plan, 3) First Floor Plan Existing and Proposed, 4) Existing Basement Plan, 5) Proposed Basement Plan, 6) Existing Second Floor Plan, 7) Proposed Second Floor Plan, 8) Existing Typical Floor Plan, 9) Proposed Typical Floor Plan, 10) Existing Third Floor Plan, 11) Proposed Third Floor Plan, 12) Existing fourth floor plan, 13) Proposed fourth floor plan, 14) Existing fifth floor plan, 15) Proposed fifth floor plan, 16) Existing sixth floor plan, 17) Proposed sixth floor plan, 18) Existing seventh floor plan, 19) Proposed seventh floor plan, 1952 (Box 134, Tube 135)
    - Floor Layout for Mechanized Material Handling, Table of Contents: First floor plan existing and proposed, First floor proposed, 1952 (Box 134, Tube 136)
    - New York Central Lines Athletic Associations Sixths Annual Track Meet to be Held At Pitt Stadium Sept. 18th 1929 (3586 FF8-1), Freight House Office Building Floor Plan (1785 JA3), The Monongahela Railway Showing Coal and Coke Operations (14193 - KF -12 and 209 - K - 393) (Box 134, Tube 137)
    - Plan of Defense Plant Corporation Area Situate in The Boroughs of Homestead and West Homestead Made for Carnegie Illinois Steel Corp ( LP- 706 and 1026), West Wing of Pittsburgh Terminal Station ( 6141 EK5), Duquesne Slag Products Company Pittsburgh Plant Layout Sheet Number 1 (133), West Wing of the Pittsburgh Terminal Station (6141 EK5), 1906-1942 (Box 134, Tube 138)
    - Bridges Replacing Moon Run Railroad Replacing Numbers 1 and 3 (G22), West Wing of Pittsburgh Terminal Station 4th floor (6141 EK5), West Wing of Pittsburgh Terminal Station showing part of glass roof and steel work over glass dome (6141 EK5), West Wing of Pittsburgh Terminal Station Cross section (6141 EK5), Montour Railroad Plan for Plate Girders of Proposed Bridge over Montour Run (G23), Plan Showing Tunnel and Retaining Wall (22), New Terminal (98 B), 1902 (Box 139)
    - Retirement of track sidings, retirement of flat cars, purchases of equipment, sale of systems, etc., 1970s (Box 144)
    - McKeesport Bridge / Repairs, blueprints; Boro of Davidson Slag; airlines at Hazelton Yard; Carbon Limestone Co. Hillsville; Freight Agents Office Building, 1948 (Box 145)
    - Standard siding agreements; construction of sidetracks, etc.; standard siding agreements; construction of sidetracks; etc., standard siding agreements; construction of sidetracks, etc.; Allegheny County Light Company; Glassport; Widening River Avenue; West End; Widening River Avenue, West End; Widening River Avenue; West End), 1902 (Box 161)
    - Lake Erie and Ohio River Canal, 1932 (Box 175)
    - Contracts with other companies; blueprints, 1920s (Box 192)
    - General Files - 547 (Meehan Boiler & Construction Co. & J.F. Cantrwell - S.J. Quinn - Sidetrack at Lowellville), 508 (Right of Way - McKees Rocks Pa), 554 (South 22nd Street Yard), 554-1 (South 22nd Street Yard), 451-4 (Diesel Repair Shop - McKees Rocks Pa), 451-4-A (Diesel Repair Shop - McKees Rocks Pa), 451-8 (Diesel Repair Shop - McKees Rocks Pa), 1950s (Box 193)
    - Old and Cancelled - 323 (Bridge Inspections), 335.1 (Pittsburgh Builders Supply KS), 336 (Lease West Newton Fr. Ste to Westmorland County Farm Bureau Coop), 367 (American Tin Plate Co. S.S. Pgh), 392 (Right of Way at Lowellville M.S.L), 399 (Photos of PUC Hearing on Lowellville crossings), 399-1 (Prop. Highway Bridge over Mahoning River, Lowellville), 403 (Pgh Coal West Newton), 413 (Road Crossing Lewis Foundry and Machine Groveton), 416 (Right of Way Sunnyside), 438 (Glenwood Bridge, Hays), 445 (Right of Way Montour Junction), 451-1 (Prop Sewers, Diesel Shop KS), 451-2 (Excavation for Diesel Shop), 451-3 (Diesel Shop KS) (Box 194)
    - Property Correspondence, Contract #3 - 67 Vipond and Vipond Inc, Contract 206-66 Aerial Map Service, 1966-1968 (Box 195)
    - Colona River Rail Transfer Plant; Colona River Rail Transfer Plant operating expenses), 1934-1936 (Box 196)
    - File Nos. 7110 - 7169-A; land leases, sidetrack agreements, bridges, tracks, grade crossings, 1925-1960 (Box 197)
    - Historical Data of the Waynesburg Southern Railroad Company - See records storage inventory sheet, 1966-1968 (Box 198)
    - File Nos. 6967 - 7104 (Standard Slag Co. Permit for Roadway on Cedar Street, Mahoning Valley Sand Co. Track Siding), 1940s-1950s (Box 200)
    - File Nos. 2758 - 2867 (Approx Cost of Pittsburgh Terminal, Matthews Run Arch at Sheppler, 1950s (Box 201)
    - File Nos. 8205 - 8365 - grade crossings; sidetrack agreements, etc., 1940s-1950s (Box 202)
    - Information pertaining to the construction of the L.E & E. RR (Files 1662-L to 1662-27-A), 1950s-1960s (Box 203)
    - Budgets 1958-61, files regarding Pittsburgh, McKeesport & Youghiogheny Railroad, 1950s (Box 204)
    - Wreck Investigation File, Alcoa, 1970s (Box 205)
    - General Files - 1166 (Abolition grade crossing on New Castle to Chawton Hwy at Taylor twp), 1182 (Market St. Crossing McKeesport), 1235 (Crossings at McKeesport, Erie, Huey, Mary, Martin, Riverton, Walnut, Dale and Agreement w/ B&O for 4th Ave), 1786-48-A (40 Hour week from 1945), 1276 (Republic Iron and Steel Co. of Haselton) 1278-A-4 (Co. Telephone employees residences), 1897-1950s (Box 206)
    - File Nos. 5105 - 5208-A-3 (Penna. Power Co., Extension of old turntable tracks at Beaver Falls, Duquesne Light Co., Controversy with the Pullman co.), 1930-1950 (Box 207)
    - Pittsburgh Steel Foundry (1795), Lake Carriers Oil Co.; Passenger Coach Tracks (1843); College Round House (1916), College Round House coal and ash plant (1916), Youngstown Sheet and Tube (1936), 1901-1907 (Box 208)
    - General Files - 7677 (Motor Trucks- Engineering Departments), 7721 (Third and Fourth Tracks Fallston to College), 7723 (Survey Along P&LE RR Permission to Enter Property), 7736 (J.P Ensing & F.G Brisbin -Personal Correspondence), 7762 (Proposed relocation of tracks through Homestead and Braddock territory), 1903-1957 (Box 209)
    - National Industrial Reclamation Act, 1930-1950 (Box 210)
    - Change crossing protection at 1st street Braddock; 2196 East Carson Street Yard, 1901-1931 (Box 211)
    - File Nos. 8513-3 to 8605 (New Car Repair Shop McKees Rocks, Lease of Property, etc), 1950s (Box 212)
    - Pittsburgh Chartiers & Youghiogheny Railway Co Damage papers McKees Rocks, Freight Car Shop McKees Rocks, etc., 1910-1950s (Box 213)
    - File Nos. 3816-4 to 3986 Lease of Land sidetrack agreement, Railroad Accident investigation reports, 1910-1960s (Box 214)
    - File Nos. 3996 to 4176; sidetrack agreements; right of way; crossings; transfers; etc. with other companies, 1900-1960 (Box 215)
    - General Files - 6777 (Colona River Rail Transfer Plant operating expenses), 6851 (YMCA general correspondence), 6891 (misc. maps and blueprints), 6927 (Electric flash butt welding for continuous rail), 6964 (Brotherhood of Railway Signalmen), 6965 (American Federation of Labor), 7040 (Wampum-Chewton Bridge over P&LE), 7074 (New River Bridge at West Street), 7114 (Pittsburgh Coal Co. constructing grade crossing over township roads), 1920-1950 (Box 216)
    - Lease of Cars, Freight Equipment files, 1980s (Box 217)
    - 1956 Zoning Ordinance; Montour Railroad and Youngstown & Southern Railroad acquisitions; main line switch; City Planning reports; crossings; property purchases; articles of agreement, 1898-1958 (Box 218)
    - Committee on valuation of railroads; inspection by ICC's Bureau of Valuation; telephone circuit locations; maintenance of way; signals; sidings in Monessen; sidetrack agreements, 1913-1959 (Box 219)
    - Youngstown Branch Bridge over Mahoning River, Car Heaters, Explosives Handling, Discontinuance Passenger Trains, Handling Investigations, 1940s (Box 220)
    - Connellsville Western Maryland abandonments, Detroit Edison Trains, Montour Railroad champion terminal study, Penn Central use of Lake Erie &Eastern, Walford Branch, Ohio River Branch, 1980s (Box 221)
    - File Nos. 5467 to 5713, 1950s-1960s (Box 222)
    - 312 (New Central Warehouse), 349 (Superior Paper Products - McKees Rocks), 1950s (Box 223)
    - General Files - 2846 (B&O crossover tracks at McKeesport connection at MK tower, switching for National Tub Co., 2833 (Rostraver storage yard re-adjustment Pgh Steel), 2874 (Reports, accounts, statements - ICC & misc. subjects), 2875 (McKeesport Freight Office), 2884 (BG Interlocking Plant), 2887 (Phoenix Glass Co.), 1909-1940 (Box 224)
    - General Files - 2495 (Crossings/ application for construction), 2499 (Mayor Pottery, Beaver Falls), 2510 (Ferrona and Sharon Branch), 1896-1907 (Box 225)
    - General Files - 5765 (Equipment Budget), 5765 (Work cars - retired, new equipment cars, pay loader, maitenance program), 5801 (Webster Fuel Supply Co Sidetrack and Lease), 5810 (Gov't Ordinance Plant), 5826 (Neville Island Branch), 5836 (United Coal Co.), 5894 (Ellwood Jct), 5904 (American Railroad Association), 1899-1953 (Box 226)
    - Old and Cancelled - 528 (West Side Belt RR), 531 (West Pittsburgh), 543 (Sherman St. Track), 547 (Falcon Foundry Co), 549 (R of W Webster), 554 (Track through J&L Property), 554 (J&L, Pittsburgh), 554-1-A (Monongahela Conn RR), 1902-1950 (Box 227)
    - File Nos. 5713-A-2 to 5931-1-A-1 (Holub Iron and Steel, Consolidation and Rearrangement of Signal Maintenance Sectors, Douglass Grade Crossings, United Coal Co Ella Mine), 1930s-1950s (Box 228)
    - File Nos. 4762-A to 4851 (Changing of Location of Highway East of Millersville, Sidetrack Agreement with Standard Steel, Exchange of R of W with B&O), 1930s-1950s (Box 229)
    - Bids regarding contracts for roadside structures, Special file on Duquesne contracting co., Right of Way Lake Erie and Eastern, 1910-1950s (Box 230)
    - Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; sidetrack agreements; articles of agreement, 1922-1959 (Box 231)
    - General Files - 2414 (Little Redstone Creek Branch), 2441 (Permits for pipe and wire crossings and making charges for same), 2445 (Townsend Company Fallston, 2495 (Crossings at Homestead), 1906 (Box 232)
    - Old and Cancelled - 1-B to 18-C (Temporary Diesel Facilities, Water Supply E. Youngstown, Hazelton Yard Masters Office), 1950s (Box 233)
    - File Nos. 4607 H to 4745-A-7 (Cherry Street Crossing, Lease of Property at Ellwood City, Grade Crossing at Ellwood City, Fence around McKees Rocks Yard), 1940s-1950s (Box 234)
    - Information on construction of the LE&E RR: 1662 (Special File - Duquesne Contr. Co and bids on grading and concrete between Cedar St and Division Streets), 1662 (LE&E RR main file surveying tracks), 1662-A-2-5 (LE&E roadbed and track), 1662-B (Vacation of streets and crossings from 1905), Early 1900s (Box 235)
    - Reports, surveys, newspaper articles, reports on costs and reports of congressional hearing of the canal, Meramec Basin Research Project 1961-1962, 1930s-1960s (Box 236)
    - Sidetrack and land leases; abandonment; changes in tracks at Elwell Branch, 1936-1966 (Box 237)
    - General Files - 1475 (Pittsburgh Tube Co siding at Monaca), 1544 (J&L siding at Aliquippa), 1544-A (Woodlawn to West Economy Highway), 1581-G-8 (Speed of trains hauling cranes on the main track), 1581-C-9 (Additions to main line and sidings, timetables, etc.), 1950s (Box 238)
    - General Files - 6107 (Cheseborough Mfg. Co. McKees Rocks), 6112 (Federal Spring Company and Standard Steel Spring), 6124 (Office Building -NYC Freight Station), 6271 (Duquesne Light Company Wire Crossing at 21st Street), 6335 (Improved and heavier weight of rail, dudley section), 6354 (Eliminating grade crossing at 21st Street), 6412 (Widening Jerome Street), 6632 (Russell Burdsall and Ward B&N Co), 6759 (Retirement costs and schedules), 6759 (Depreciation and fixed costs ICC), 1912-1945 (Box 239)
    - Old and Cancelled PC&Y 349-H to 349-N (various sidetrack agreements), 1950s (Box 240)
    - Old and Cancelled PC&Y 312.22-D to 312.22-W (Duquesne Light Crossings at Chestnut Street, Kennedy and Guthrie Station, and Railroad Street), 1940s-1950s (Box 241)
    - General Files - 3997 (Matthew's Gravity Carrier Co. Ellwood City / Matthew's Conveyor Co.), 1911 (Box 242)
    - File Nos. 1371 - 1621 (Under crossings, Oil house at college, Right of Way at North Webster, etc), 1910-1930 (Box 243)
    - File Nos. 5022 - 5104 (Lease of Land, Report on the Development of Water Resources at the Mahoning River, Upper Ohio Valley Association, 1910-1950 (Box 244)
    - File Nos. 2279 - 2387 (Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission, Aliquippa Yard, etc.), 1910-1950 (Box 245)
    - Books, studies, and surveys for Lake Erie and Ohio River Canal, 1940-1960 (Box 246)
    - Train Accidents, 1965 (Box 247)
    - General Files - 1064 (Universal Sanitary Mfg. Co reconstruction of trestle property conveyance, private roadway), 1064 - A (Universal Rundle 12" water line), 1064-1 (Grade Crossing), 1068-1 (Kelsy-Hayes Development Port Vue), 1068-A (McKeesport Tin Plate and J&L sidetrack), 1076 (American Steel and Wire Co. track changes), 1902-1947 (Box 248)
    - Old and Cancelled - 573 (Fire at Newell coal mine), 577 (Mesta Machine Co. discharge into Streets Run), 582 (Monaca Freight Station), 588 (Mon River Coal and Coke), 590-B-1 (Pittsburgh Steel Co.), 607 (Mon River Coal and Coke), 623 (Right of Way South Side), 661 (Commercial Sash and Door), 669 (Right of Way Edenburg), 680 (Pittsburgh Railways wire crossings), 732 (A. Hayden Elizabeth Siding), 733 (Right of Way J. Sinnott Gibsonton), 757 (Pvt. grade crossing, Whitsett Junction), 769 (4th Street crossing Pittsburgh), 775 (Right of Way Rostraver), 791 (Right of Way Demler), 802 (General Yard office KS), 1898-1958 (Box 249)
    - File Nos. 2621-4 to 2745-A (3rd Street undercrossing Glassport, Co Interlocking Plant, Drainage Monessen, RK Interlocking), 1950s (Box 250)
    - Federal Long housemen's and Harbor Worker's Compensation Act; Whirler Crane; sidetrack agreements; snow removal; grade crossings; track proposals, 1922-1958 (Box 251)
    - Old and Cancelled - 805 (Valley Electric, Fallston), 806 (Ohio Valley Supply), 809 (Struthers Highway Bridge), 810 (Raising P&W Tracks at Struthers Bridge), 829 (Water Station Port Vue), 832 (Jacobs Creek Scale), 833 (Speers Run Branch), 839 (O'Neil and Patterson Tipple), 841 (Right of way Homestead), 859 (Right of Way American Window Glass), 868 (Right of way Layton), 885 (Continental Can Co.), 886 (Electric Power Lines), 887 (Overhead crossing, J&L Tunnel north end), 889 (Right of way Becks Run), 890 (New Committee on Slag), 903 (Right of Way, Bridgewater), 943A (Jepco of Pa.), 1899-1953 (Box 252)
    - General Files - 2517 (Woodlawn Passenger Station), 2565 (Western Union Telephone Co. contract), 2621 (Various changes including street crossings or bridges at 2nd and 3rd streets at Beaver Leopard and Lion lane at Bridgewater), 2621 (Snyder's record on steel work for bridges), 2631 (Wire crossings- Youngstown consolidated gas and electric at Lowellville and Bentley, MSL, also wires from N. Castle Jct.), 2636 (Grade crossings at West Newton -Hwy. Rt. 118), 1908-1942 (Box 253)
    - General Files - 595 (Sewers, McKees Rocks), 653 (J&L Tunnel), 714 (Lightweight freight cars-same for clearances reports freight cars cleaned), 1920s-1950s (Box 254)
    - 8255 (Defense Plant Corp foot walk, alcohol lines, steam lines, gas line on Raccoon Creek), 8261 (United Engineering and foundry contract to serve plant at Sherman and New Castle), 8288 (New passenger and freight layout at Homestead), 8375 (Amper Iron and Metal Company, proposed lease of land and tracks and Southwest Compressed Steel Corp), 1940s (Box 255)
    - 1662-33 (Coal and ash handling, LE&E RR/ Lansingville), 1662-43 (Investments as per agreement), 1662-42-A (General File, Mahoning Valley Agreements), 1662-70 (Yard Office, train men and car mens buildings), 1940s-1960s (Box 256)
    - Surveys, studies, reports, maps, and geological reports of the Lake Erie and Ohio River Canal, 1950s (Box 257)
    - 399-A (Proposed Sewers at Lowellville), 418 (Brownville Junction Yard), 434 (McKeesport Freight House), 451-1 (Diesel Repair Shop, McKees Rocks), 1950s (Box 258)
    - Car shops and buildings; agreements with companies; sidetrack agreements; siding; connections; grade crossings, 1890-1958 (Box 259)
    - Personal Injury Record Cards, Car and Locomotive, 1943-1974 (Box 260)
    - Correspondence on thefts and vandalism, maintenance, construction, 1899-1957 (Box 285a-285b)
    - Expense reports, track change proposals, and correspondence between PL&E and Baltimore & Ohio Railroad on use of tracks, 1940s (Box 286b)
    - Railroad and terminal maintenance and construction, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers public notices, correspondence with chief of engineers, 1900-1950 (Box 287a)
    - Maintenance and construction, 1940s (Box 287b)
    - Records of 1981 'Great Train Ride', contracts and agreements with Pennsylvania Railroad Company, study of Jones & Laughlin Steel Company, General Notices, track changes, matters of Pittsburgh, Chartiers, and Youghiogheny Railroad Company and Gateway Yard, 1927-1984 (Box 296a)
    - Correspondence on car movements, track changes, legal issues, 1983 Weed and Bush Control Program, and "5,000,000th Freight Car"/Gateway Yard Celebration (1966); rosters and seniority lists, notices and bulletins, 1924-1983 (Box 296b)
    - Daily locomotive reports, freight car inspections, Express Truck Maintenance Manual, Waukesha Engines Manual (1951), freight car and work equipment records, and purchasers of Little Kanawha Syndicate and Buckhannon & Northern Railroads, 1914-1986 (Box 298b)
    - State road crossings, changes in grade crossings, properties secured, correspondence with other railroads, engineator wiring diagrams, parts including joints, transfers, and track fastenings, and matters of Montour Railroad Company and their engineering department, 1913-1951 (Box 300b)
    - City of Pittsburgh granted authorizations for building projects; Frank Virant's personal items, 1905-1940 (Box 329b)
    - Correspondence concerning Lake Erie & Ohio River Ship Canal and proposed improvement of Beaver and Mahoning Rivers, change of rails through "SI" Interlocking Plant; accounts and payrolls, 1933-1949 (Box 334a)
    - Records of 40-hour work week decision; correspondence concerning Pennsylvania Railroad bridge at Beaver Falls and New Brighton, bridge in Homestead, train accidents, and locomotive parts, 1898-1960 (Box 342b)
    - Newspaper clippings by Burrelles Clipping Service, 1965-1967 (Box 352-353)
    - Correspondence of Industrial Engineering dept. to the office of the president regarding Upper Ohio River Canal, 1936-1941 (Box 354)
    - Construction of the Lake Erie and Ohio River Canal papers: correspondence, plans, legal matters, hearings, 1960s (Box 356)
    - Papers concerning construction of upper Ohio River Canal, 1930s (Box 358)
    - Papers pertaining to Lake Erie and Ohio River Canal, 1941-1945, 1960s (Box 360-361)
    - Reports and correspondence regarding construction of dam and reservoir in The Mahoning River Basin, OH; West Branch Reservoir; Upper Ohio Valley Assoc. Reports and correspondence, U.S. Senate Committee on Public Works sessions, 1935-1965 (Box 362)